Hello, this is financial planner Patrick Munro, checking in with you today on reverse annuity mortgages, really known as reverse mortgages for short.
This creative financial planning tool is available to Americans that are 62 years of age or older.
Usually, there's several key banks that will participate in this program.
What happens is many of the senior Americans that are out there have already paid off their house, but home equity has no rate of return, so make your house pay yourself back over time.
Your income is usually compromised when you're retired, so the mortgage company takes a mortgage on your home, and provides you either a credit line or a monthly income that you don't have to make a mortgage payment on.
It's very unique.
The interest bills on the back end of the mortgage, and what happens is you're allowed to age in place as a senior American.
You can stay in the home for as long as you wish, receive those payments from your reverse annuity mortgage, and you can also live there until your spouse passes on as well.
No worries for your family, because when they inherit the family home, they have up to a year to refinance and pay out the reverse mortgage.
It's a very useful tool that helps your family members not have a burden for your care later in life, because you've turned your home into a financial planning tool using the reverse annuity mortgage.
This is financial planner, Patrick Munro.